Guide to the Toni Asante Lightfoot Poetry Ephemera collection, 1991-2004 MS2233
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Toni Asante Lightfoot Poetry Ephemera collection
1991-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Lightfoot, Toni Asante
MS2233
0.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains postcards, fliers, and poems related to poetry readings and other performances by Toni Asante Lightfoot and other local poets and writers.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Toni Asante Lightfoot donated this collection in 2007
Historical or Biographical Note
Toni Asante Lightfoot is a graduate of Cave Canem African American Writer's Workshop and a teacher of writing workshops. She is co-founder of the poetry collective the Modern Urban Griots. She is a leader in the national arts organization, Blackout Arts Collective. Ms. Lightfoot was President of the African American Writers Guild, founded by Marita Golden. In November 2002 Lightfoot became the Business and Outreach Manager Guild Complex in Chicago.
Lightfoot has authored several books including two collections of poems entitled Kiss My Ears Like Jazz and Unearthing Me.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains newspaper articles, magazine articles, poetry, fliers, letters, playbills, programs, and photographs related to several poetry reading groups and other poetry related activities within Washington, D.C. Two prominent groups are It's Your Mug and Modern Urban Griots. It's Your Mug was a poetry reading series. The Modern Urban Griots described itself as "... a family of poets who came to know each other at It's Your Mug, a coffee house in the historic Georgetown Section of Washington, D.C. The seven members came together in the name of poetry and mutual love for the art and its performance. They are: Jane Alberdeston, Holly Bass, Danny Boylen II, Twain Dooley, Brandon D. Johnson, Toni Asante Lightfoot, and Lori Tsang."
Collection Organization
This collection is composed of several folders and does not have separate series.
Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Poetry; Lightfoot, Toni Asante; Bass, Holly; Brooks, Gwendolyn
- 10th Anniversary National Black Theatre Festival playbills, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- D.C. Poetry fliers, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  General note
  This folder contains fliers for different events and performance groups in the city.
- Exhibit catalog: Lou Stovall Heroes and Teachers, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- It's Your Mug, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  This poetry reading group held a 10 year reunion in 2004
- Letters to Toni Asante Lightfoot from students at Duke Ellington School of the Arts, 04/1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Magazine articles about Black artists, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes the magazine Humanities vol. 15 No. 3 May/June 1994 with numerous articles by and about Gwendolyn Brooks.
- Modern Urban Griots Poetry and Performance Collective, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Black Arts Festival program, 06/28/1996-07/07/1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newspaper articles, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Painted Bride Art Center and Kennedy Center programs, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Seventh Annual Black Writer's Conference, 10/23/1997-10/25/1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Spoken Word Sacred Circle World Festival III, 10/29/1999-10/31/1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Toni Asante Lightfoot, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  This folder contains poems, event calendars, and fliers related to the work of Toni Asante Lightfoot.
- It's Your Mug ten year reunion posters, 01/31/2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)